# **BRYCE MYERS | SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

COLORADO SPRINGS, CO | 719-648-9882 | brycemyengineer@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

### SUMMARY

Highly motivated, self-driven full-stack software engineer with foundational knowledge in front-end and back-end programming, gained through a full intensive software engineering bootcamp. Seeking to apply skillful attention to detail, team collaboration, and resource management garnered from over five years as a Communications Director.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, and frameworks such as Bootstrap

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, and PostgreSQL

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Node Package Manager, and Visual Studio Code

### **EXPERIENCE**

Thinkful

# **Software Engineering Certificate**

10/2022 - 03/2023

- Learned software development industry best practices/standards in a full-time, five-month program.
- Completed modules and assessments while learning new languages and frameworks under guidance of a senior software engineer in a mentor-student relationship.
- Completed real-world simulation, hands-on role-based, scenario-based projects, and virtual labs.

As part of the program, produced professional projects from concept to completion, including:

- o Library application | Local Library |
  - Technology: JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap, HTML5, Node.js
  - Assembled functionality for a library application including search, review, check out.
  - Created search, sorting functions to allow users to see book availability and ratings.
  - Coded using JavaScript functions to enable library expansion without requiring code refactoring.

### o Decoder Ring Application | Decoder Ring |

- Technology: JavaScript ES6
- Used JavaScript to create functions for converting letter characters and/or numbers into others.
- Developed a decoder that works as a Caesar shift, Polybius square, and Substitution.

# o Thinkful BnB Application | Thinkfulbnb |

- Technology: Flexbox, HTML5, CSS3
- Formatted the Thinkfulbnb site implemented appropriate media queries for responsive design.
- Created a page layout using Flexbox, using appropriate input types for forms too.
- Utilized a mobile-first development approach

#### Academy Christian Church

Colorado Springs, CO 02/2020 – 09/2022

### **Visual Communications Director**

- Edited website template to update, prepare audio/video recordings for listeners in a timely fashion.
- Recorded and edited informative videos weekly with relevant updates to keep listeners connected.
- Prepared for weekly events including stage lighting, video, remote cameras, online streaming so that we were ready and equipped to deliver the best possible experience to those in attendance.
- Oversaw troubleshooting tech issues that fellow staff had with devices.
- Organized and then implemented large stage designs for special occasions in order to help bring to life the surroundings of attendees.

### Tek Experts

Colorado Springs, CO

### **Customer Service Representative**

08/2019 - 02/2020

- Helped customers resolve a variety of issues and errors that are related to Microsoft Azure in a prompt and timely manner.
- Interacted with both customers and employees to help resolve issues and come to solutions that are both helpful and even empowering to customers in order to help them feel more confident using Azure.
- Adhered to strict customer confidentiality in order to make sure we protect our customers. Able to look into our database of online knowledge to help solve problems when solutions are not readily available.

### Host

- Made sure our restaurant guests were seated at a table in an active server's section as quickly as possible.
- Used our in-house waitlist system, record customer contact information to alert them when their table
  was ready as well as update the status of each table to help servers and other hosts maintain a smooth
  process.
- Used extensive knowledge of the menu to effectively take orders over the phone and ring them into the system for pick up.
- Exceptional interpersonal communication skills were necessary in order to interact with many guests and team members to create a memorable experience for our guests.

Heuberger Subaru

Colorado Springs, CO 01/2019 - 04/2019

**Lot Tech** 

- Moved and cleaned vehicles to help make the buying experience for customers as enjoyable and easy as possible.
- Ran errands around town to drop off and pick up cars for repairs, working and communicating well with my team to accomplish tasks efficiently.

Pikes Peak Christian Church

Colorado Springs, CO

07/2015 - 12/2018

- **Associate Creative Director** 
  - Managed and maintained communication via both online and internal channels.
  - Created graphics, videos and marketing materials.
  - Monitored social media/Youtube accounts.
  - Designed and implemented a smart device app.
  - Aided executive level leadership in communications related issues.
  - Connected and coordinated freelance personnel.

**EDUCATION** 

Thinkful: Certificate, Software Engineering

03/2023

Ozark Christian College: Bachelor of Arts, Christian Ministry

05/2008